foreign
[Music]
a couple years ago I visited a lavender
farm that was absolutely full of sweet
little Buzzing Bees I brought home
several jars of Wildflower honey finding
the taste to be quite unique
I don't use honey very often in my
cooking so this winter I decided to
break out those old jars and use them in
a recipe for honey wine
foreign
[Music]
if I can name three things I deeply
enjoy in my home life it is candles
books and delicious warm drinks so this
was a fitting way to spend a winter
afternoon and pay homage to the coming
spring
foreign
to last week and chat about the
guidelines I follow in order to spend
mindfully throughout my day as Luke and
I are currently attempting to stay on a
budget and plan for future family
[Music]
firstly when it comes to decorating your
home I keep in mind this perspective
when I'm tempted to impulsively spend on
household items or add clutter to my
space
the best most peaceful and loving
environment is cultivated with good
memories a lot of love friendship and
laughter
a home that nurtures these things is all
that is really needed I find the same
applies to clothing no amount of New
pieces will disguise the soul that isn't
thriving and seeking joy in the everyday
an open heart a positive outlook and
kind words are what make people
beautiful
items while practical and useful cannot
offer this to us
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
if I wish to impulsively spend I write
down the item I'm considering and if
possible walk away I give myself a
couple days to think about if I really
want it and very often my feelings
change and I realize that my inclination
was simply coming from a place that
wasn't as mindful
thank you
[Music]
When shopping I ask myself is there an
alternative to this item I can use or
make at home I find this question
helpful in regards to buying storage
containers and more practical home items
often I have boxes or things laying
about the house that I can repurpose if
only I consider my options
in regards to clothes I try to mend and
fix what I already have often on
websites like thredup and secondhand
shops I can keep an eye out for brands
that I like for example several of my
dresses are from a company that I don't
often support directly but pop up on
thrifting websites regularly I also have
some very nice boots I take in for
repairs sometimes it makes a huge
difference in my spending
foreign
[Music]
as you know I buy thrifted items when
possible my local shops are always
overflowing and more than happy for
someone to take something away as I
peruse items I often stop to wonder if
what I'm adding to my home would make it
feel cluttered or add significant extra
stress in regards to cleaning it helps
me keep what I buy to a minimum of
course I value having home with items
that are special to me I'm certainly not
a minimalist my love of vintage items
and art supplies would not allow it but
I do try to keep surfaces clear so that
I can tidy easily
[Music]
I find developing a meditative or
spiritual practice always helps me
disconnect in a healthy way from
material things and remember that only
the essentials I really needed for a
full life
I also try to be aware of how
advertisements instill a scarcity
mindset in me insinuating that I need an
item to be happier fulfilled this is not
true and once I'm aware I find myself
naturally shifting my habits and
reflecting on my own insecurities and
resolving those in ways other than
consumerism while it might take
initially some self-restraint and
dedication I find the benefits are
overwhelmingly positive
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
I have been pleasantly surprised by how
simple and easy it has been to make this
need I think the challenging part as
always in a house with a lot of pets is
to make sure everything stays clean and
no cat paws touch everything because I
have such a curious cat and she has a
tendency to get into anything I do so
thankfully it all worked out and we are
gonna get some Mead but it was really
fun to make and the honey that I used is
local honey comes from all the
wildflowers in the area and I just love
the taste of it so I'm very excited to
see how it turns out I only have about
27 26 days to wait now until it is ready
to put in the bottles and I have created
my label because fairy nectar I think is
the very appropriate term for this type
of drink it is so delicious I tend to
get an upset stomach if I have you know
any substantial amount of a drink so I
I'm just going to have a very small
amount and I think that is how this sort
of drink is meant to be enjoyed anyway
just in very small little cups as a
dessert as you can see there has been a
bees and Beeswax theme to this video I
have received quite a few beeswax
candles lately you may not know this if
you have bought beeswax candles at the
store that are mixed with other waxes
but when you get completely natural 100
beeswax the smell of the candles is so
delicious you do not need any added
scent because it just fills your home
with just this amazing amazing Aroma I
hope you enjoyed these little tips that
I shared about mindful spending and how
I like to think about my budget it has
been a year of so many changes budget
wise with finally being able to get a
home and so we have had a lot more to
think about and so it has been a good
challenge but a challenge nonetheless to
rethink everything about our spending
and do our best to economize where we
can and live within our means as much as
possible I definitely rely on my Etsy
shop in order to keep creating these
videos so I definitely appreciate every
one of you who has supported my shop
there's never any obligation but there
is much appreciation so thank you for me
I find it to be extremely helpful to
grow in awareness of advert advertising
and how so much large-scale advertising
Works in order to create insecurities in
ourselves I think this is true for
everyone but I could see how it can be
extra intense for women because there is
so much clothing and cosmetics
advertisements that often send messages
that make you feel like you need these
products in order to feel better about
yourself or be more acceptable to others
I find as well it is helpful to journal
about my spending habits and things like
that I think I remember when I was much
younger that I would sometimes have this
feeling that if I had this one piece of
clothing it would just make me feel so
much better and that feeling was always
short term because all it took was a
couple days weeks months later to go
into another store and see another item
that I was just sure was going to make
all the difference I think we do fall
into that cycle quite easily of thing
thinking that these physical things will
somehow ameliorate feelings inside and
as far as I know it has never made a
lasting impact the only things that have
led to more long-term fulfillments is
working on my own confidence and my own
self-esteem I think developing those
feelings come from within and to develop
a practice of meditation or even your
own spirituality if you are a spiritual
person and if not just more grounding of
yourself and really wondering where your
feelings come from what can you do that
is not related to simply giving in to
consumeristic tendencies that can
nurture you I find for me getting a lot
more involved in my community getting a
passionate about projects that I have in
mind you know reforestation projects
conservation projects and being part of
those things and volunteering really
makes an enormous difference of course
personally my more spiritual life is
extremely important to me and I do
always say that reticently because I
know that not everyone is inclined in
that direction and not everyone has any
interest in developing that so I simply
share that from my perspective it has
always been extremely helpful but if
that is not for you I know that
grounding meditation and focus exercises
it can help in getting in touch with
your feelings your inner thoughts and
sometimes that can be a little bit
alarming it's almost like it might stir
up a lot of feelings to spend time with
a lot of things that you have brushed
under the rug for many years I know for
me really facing my tendency towards
anxiousness and stress made those
feelings come up and feel more difficult
to handle in the short term but in the
long term I've learned coping mechanisms
and strategies to change my thinking and
become a lot more positive and peaceful
and grounded while I deeply value so
many physical things in my life I'd love
to go to thrift shops I love candles I
love books I don't need them and I'm
always making sure that if I'm receiving
something I can make plans to give
something as well especially within my
own Community I am sending you so much
love I have such exciting news and it's
really hard not to talk about it so I
will see you very soon next week in
about six or seven days I will share the
news and it is just gonna be the most
amazing thing if you have a guess of
what it is do share it down below
because I do want to talk about it even
though I can't so
stay tuned I'm sending all of you my
love sending well wishes for a lovely
week and I will see you soon goodbye
[Music]
foreign
yeah